<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:ns0="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Casey Farms - Rooks County, Kansas</title>
		<link>https://www.caseyfarms.us/</link>
		<description>Casey Farms was established in 1878 in the Corning Township, Rooks County, Kansas. We are a family farming operation driven by six generations of hard work.</description>
		<item>
			<title>Grain Without a Buyer: Navigating Sorghum’s Export Fallout in 2025</title>
			<link>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0020.html</link>
			<guid>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0020.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 1 Nov 2025 15:00:00 CST</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<img src="https://www.caseyfarms.us/images/Blog-S-020.jpg" alt="Grain Without a Buyer: Navigating Sorghum’s Export Fallout in 2025" /><br/>As the 2025 harvest season unfolds across North Central Kansas, farmers are facing a perfect storm of economic and environmental pressures. From soaring input and volatile markets, it has been nothing short of challenging.</br>Over the last three years, grain-related income has plummeted while chemical, seed, fertilizer, equipment, and application costs have surged. The American Relief Act of December 2024 offered some support, but direct payments covered less than 1/3 of last season’s row crop losses. With inflation and interest rates rising it is tightening credit.  Some farmers are downsizing, restructuring loans, and there is an increase of farm-related bankruptcies.</br>To compound the problem President Trump’s administration has engaged in a trade war with China – the largest export partner of the United States.  The standoff between the countries has impacted the agriculture sector – with major reduction in sorghum and soybean exports.</br>The basis on sorghum is, frankly, ridiculous. Uncertainty in export demand—especially from China—has led elevators across Kansas to discount sorghum well below futures. This weak basis compounds the problem of high costing inputs, leaving producers with little or no margin for error.</br>The impact of rural communities and farmers is real.  The path forward looks bleak...]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bushels and Beyond: The Year Corn Broke the Charts</title>
			<link>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0019.html</link>
			<guid>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0019.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 1 Sep 2025 15:00:00 CST</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<img src="https://www.caseyfarms.us/images/Blog-S-019.jpg" alt="Bushels and Beyond: The Year Corn Broke the Charts" /><br/>Corn production for grain is forecast at 16.7 billion bushels, up 13 percent from 2024, which if realized would be the highest production for grain on record for the United States. Based on conditions as of August 1, the yield is forecast at a record high of 188.8 bushels per acre, up 9.5 bushels from last year’s 179.3 bushels. Total planted area, at 97.3 million acres, is up 2 percent from the previous estimate and up 7 percent from the previous year. Area harvested for grain is forecast at 88.7 million acres, up 2 percent from the previous forecast and up 7 percent from the previous year, (USDA Crop Production – Released August 12, 2025).</br>As a result, corn and sorghum took a nosedive in the early part of the week, only to rebound by Friday.  Yes…you read that correctly.  The USDA announces the largest corn crop in the history of the United States, plus an acreage increase of 2 million acres, and the prices plunge and then miraculously rebound in 3-4 days?  Obviously, the markets anticipated a bin buster.  The subsequent rebound suggests that prices may have reached or are near their summer lows.  So where does that leave farmers?  Obviously, lower prices mean negative net returns, and unfortunately implementing cost-saving measures to improve net returns is out of the question at this stage. Farmers should plan for a continued environment of low corn/sorghum prices in the near term and remain vigilant to shifting factors that could change the trajectory in this ever-cyclical agricultural market.  Some would say that structured and proactive marketing plans work.  Of course, that would depend on seasonal timing and a bit of luck.  Probably the biggest factor is exports trends for the next three months.  As they say, stay tune...]]></description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nephew Nate Matlack joins the Chiefs</title>
			<link>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0018.html</link>
			<guid>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0018.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 18:00:00 CST</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.caseyfarms.us/images/Blog-S-018.jpg" alt="Nephew Nate Matlack joins the Chiefs" /><br/>Nate Matlack joins the Kansas City Chiefs in a story that blends grit with professional ambition.  Nate Matlack, my nephew, officially joined the Kansas City Chiefs earlier this week, a moment thats as thrilling for our family. Go Chiefs!]]></description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rain Makes Grain</title>
			<link>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0017.html</link>
			<guid>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0017.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 18:00:00 CST</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.caseyfarms.us/images/Blog-S-017.jpg" alt="Rain Makes Grain" /><br/>No more than 7 days ago, the NWS was predicting an extended period of high temperatures and low precipitation. The 15- and 30- day forecast looked miserable with several days forecasted above 100 degrees. However, this summer's weather patterns appear to be erratic and difficult to predict. Within the last 5 days, we have received approximately 4 inches of rain…]]></description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Here we go again</title>
			<link>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0016.html</link>
			<guid>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0016.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 18:00:00 CST</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.caseyfarms.us/images/Blog-S-016.jpg" alt="Here we go Again..." /><br/>In 2025, the agriculture sector is facing unprecedented challenges. Since 2022 farm related income from grain sales has plummeted, while input costs (chemical, seed, and application costs) have increased exponentially. The result is revenues well below breakeven points which are negatively affecting large segments of rural America.]]></description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>USDA forecasting lower 2025 Revenue...</title>
			<link>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0015.html</link>
			<guid>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0015.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 18:00:00 CST</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.caseyfarms.us/images/Blog-S-015.jpg" alt="USDA forecasting lower 2025 Revenue" /><br/>USDA Economic Research Service is projecting a decrease of $1.8 billion in farm sector income in 2025. That would make the third consecutive year of decreased revenue, since hitting a record high in 2022. Total crop receipts are projected down $5.6 billion (-2.3%) from 2024. While animal income is expected to improve slightly by $3.8 billon (+1.4%). The only saving grace, is direct government payments are forecasted to increase in 2025.]]></description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Farm Crisis 2025?</title>
		  <link>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0014.html</link>
		  <guid>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0014.html</guid>
		  <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jan 2025 18:00:00 CST</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.caseyfarms.us/images/Blog-S-014.jpg" alt="Farm Crisis 2025" /><br/>Like the 1980s the term farm crisis has re-emerged in 2025. The primary concern is the drop in commodity prices, with wheat, sorghum, and corn plunging nearly 37% from 2022 thru 2024. Furthermore, our nation is struggling with inflation and seed, chemicals, and fertilizer are not exempt. As such, there is growing concern in the agriculture sector about financial stability in 2025.]]></description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dog Days of Summer</title>
			<link>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0013.html</link>
			<guid>https://www.caseyfarms.us/Blog-0013.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 18:00:00 CST</pubDate>
			<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.caseyfarms.us/images/Blog-S-013.jpg" alt="Dog Days of Summer" /><br/>The forecast for next week looks very similar, with the National Weather Service forecasting an Excessive Heat Warning with temperatures nearing 105-108. This sudden spike in heat has created a perilous situation for cattle and crops. This not only affects the local economy but also has broader implications for those that make a living on the family farm.]]></description>
		</item>	
	</channel>
</rss>